# **IGOR SCHKRAB**

+1 778 321 2410 | igorsalves87@gmail.com www.igorschkrab.com linkedin.com/in/igorsalves87

# Summary

**Senior Software Developer & Team Lead** with over **10 years of professional experience** in full-cycle software development, project management and team leadership. Constantly aiming to exceed expectations of my clients and peers, I thrive at solving business problems and working hard bringing a sincere passion for the IT industry. Effective communicator distinguished for integrating technical education with business acumen in order to deliver top notch solutions and drive innovation in fast-paced environments.

## Skills

- Java
- Spring / Spring Boot
- JPA / Hibernate
- Mulesoft
- Junit / Spock / Geb
- Jenkins
- MongoDB
- Maven / Gradle
- Web Services (REST / SOAP)
- SQL (Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL)
- Apache Camel (Light ESB)
- Docker

## Experience

#### **Software Developer**

## Firefly Software - Vancouver, Canada

- Development of new features
- Refactoring legacy code and creating unit test to increase code coverage
- Participating in process improvements (gitflow, code review, unit tests)
- Documenting development process (deployment, features, projects)
- Working closely with QA team in order to deliver quality code in a timely manner

#### **Customer Success Software Engineer**

#### June 2018 to April 2020

April 2020 to current

#### Tasktop - Vancouver, Canada

- Development of specific integrations between DevOps tools for specific clients
- Improving development process into an agile environment
- Dockerizing environments for testing and demo
- Create software documentations to clients and third party customers
- Create automated tests and ensure code is well tested before committing any code changes,
- Conduct code reviews to ensure code is written according to industry and company standards and to ensure the team is using shared libraries for maximum re-use
- Participating in the interviewing process

#### **Java Software Engineer**

#### Mar 2018 to June 2018

#### Incognito Software - Vancouver, Canada

- Requirements gathering and analysis
- Create specifications, provide estimates, and develop software for those specifications
- Create automated tests and ensure code is well tested before committing any code changes,
- Conduct code reviews to ensure code is written according to industry and company standards and to ensure the team is using shared libraries for maximum re-use

• Mentor less experienced developers and be a key role in onboarding new hires

#### **Senior Software Developer**

#### Mar 2015 to Mar 2018

#### Middleware 360 Solutions Inc. - Vancouver, Canada

- Lead Developer & Technical Leader (team of 4)
- Software Maintenance
- Designing application together with clients
- Managing priorities to deliver value to the client
- Always helping coworkers to get through issues and leading with deadlines, delivering value to our clients making sure they're happy and satisfied with the product

## **Lead Developer & Systems Analyst Consultant**

Feb 2013 to Nov 2014

#### Gtcon - São Paulo, Brazil

- End-to-end software development for an insurance company
- Developed new features on a project basis
- Bridge between business analysis and development team
- Developed front and back end features
- Improved the internal software development process by talking to business analysts and developer to make sure we had a clear communication creating a better environment between the team and improving the tickets being delivered

#### **Lead Developer**

Apr 2012 to Feb 2013

#### Solutis - Salvador, Brazil

- Lead developer (team of 4)
- Direct contact with internal clients to explore needs
- Software maintenance
- Gathered product requirements
- Took care of the system after the leader left the team and Implemented Scrum methodology, being able to get a quicker feedback from clients making sure we were delivering value

## **Senior Developer**

May 2011 to Apr 2012

## Avansys - Salvador, Brazil

- Bridge between business analysis and the development team
- Go-to person to help other developers
- Lead developer (team of 4)
- Software maintenance
- Created the Software Development Model and specified internal coding patterns and best practices to be used amongst entire team making it easier for new developer to get up to speed with the project

## Developer

Jul 2010 to Apr 2011

#### Potenza - Salvador, Brazil

- Adapted and Upgrading an existing software
- Detected common errors between systems
- Increased overall team efficiency by creating documents for new developers
- Suggested and helped to apply some changes to the development process as we had separate teams to handle the software and the database, creating a considered delay in communication when the team needed to apply some changes to the data structure

#### Developer

Oct 2007 to Jun 2010

#### Reconcavo Technology Institute - Salvador, Brazil

- End-to-end software life cycle
- Business analysis & Requirements gathering
- Project management
- Development and Testing

• Direct contact with the clients of our client, which is a really big responsibility, to make sure we were delivering what he expected, solving bugs and delegating tasks to have problems solved as soon as possible

# **Education and Training**

## **Specialist at Distributed Web Components**

College DeVry I Ruy Barbosa - Red River Campus - Salvador, BA - Brazil Incomplete (1 subject left - Reason: Moved to another city)

## **Bachelor of Science, Computer Science**

2010

College DeVry I Ruy Barbosa - Red River Campus - Salvador, BA - Brazil

## **Solutions Architect Academy**

2013

Globalcode - São Paulo, SP - Brazil

## **Activities and Certificates**

• Sun Certified for Java Programmer 5.0

- MCD Integration and API Associate (Mulesoft)
- Promoted to Senior Software Developer role at Middleware 360
- Promoted to Technical Leader at Middleware 360 (QuadReal Project)
- Books Listening (Audible) at least two books per month